William Hobart Royce Papers
William Hobart Royce Papers
1834-1963
Royce, William Hobart, 1878-
55.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American author, bibliographer, book collector, founder of the Balzac Society of America. Correspondence (1901-1962) from Marcel Bouteron, Edwin Preston Dargan, Jean Pommier, Stefan Zweig, and others, mostly Balzac collectors and scholars; writings (1905-1962), including articles, and books on Balzac, as well as translations; and material relating to the Balzac Society of America, including its Bulletin (1940-1962) and membership files (1940-1962).
149555
Biographical History
William Hobart Royce (1878-1963) was an American author, bibliographer, book collector, and founder of the Balzac Society of America.
Born on March 20, 1878, in Springfield, Massachusetts, Royce completed his formal education by graduating from the Springfield High School in 1897. Later he would write that his "only university has been the New York Public Library."
After some bookstore experience in Springfield, Royce entered the book trade in New York City, spending twelve years with the book department of the American News Company and seven years with the Lexington Book Shop. In 1917 he joined the Gabriel Wells rare book firm, for which he was manager for over 30 years. Wells and Royce shared a deep interest in Balzac (it was Wells who saved Balzac's house at Passy from destruction), and during this time the firm became the center of the sale of Balzaciana. Royce himself assembled a major collection of Balzac material. His Balzac library was sold and his papers were donated by his daughters Eva Allen Royce and Abbie Anna Royce to Syracuse University's.
Royce's published works ran to over a dozen titles. His books on Balzac include Balzac, Immortal (1926), A Balzac Bibliography (1929), Indexes to A Balzac Bibliography (1930), and Balzac as He Should Be Read (1946). Royce published over a half dozen volumes of his own verse; he wrote verse also under the pen names Willie Penmore and Cassandra.
In 1940 Royce founded The Balzac Society of America. For over two decades he served as its president and edited its Bulletin. In recognition of his contributions to Balzac bibliography and collecting, Royce was awarded the Cross of the Legion of Honor in 1935 and was made an honorary citizen of Issoudun, the French provincial town which is the setting of La Rabouilleuse.
Royce was married in 1908 to Eda Maria Wallin. They had two daughters, Eva Allen Royce and Abbie Anna Royce, M.D. He died on 28 Jan 1963.
Royce was the subject of a "Profile" article in The New Yorker, Apr 1, 1933, pp. 18-21. For further biographical and anecdotal material, see Life, 24 Feb 1947, pp. 19-20, 22; and "Brooklyn Balzac" by Stefan Zweig in Who, vol. 1, no. 3 (Jun 1941), p. 48.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The William Hobart Royce Papers, 1834-1963, contain correspondence, autograph (handwritten) material, Balzaciana, material related to the American Balzac Society, printed material, writings, and memorabilia. Royce's arrangement of the material has been preserved. Royce maintained detailed records of his collection and numbered many of the items. These numbers whenever extant are retained in the following inventory.
Correspondence, 1901-1962, is international in scope, largely with book dealers, collectors and scholars, often Balzac specialists. The bulk of the letters date from the years 1927 to 1957. Principal correspondents include Marcel Bouteron, curator of the Lovenjoul Collection at the Chateau de Chantilly; Edwin Preston Dargan (the "Vautrin" of the correspondence, who, like other of Royce's correspondents, adopted a Balzacian pen name), professor of French literature at the University of Chicago and editor of the University of Chicago Studies in Balzac; Walter Scott Hastings (pen name "Daniel D'Arthez"), professor of modern languages at Princeton University; Jean Pommier, successor to Bouteron at Chantilly; and Stefan Zweig, Austrian writer. To these and to other of his correspondents, Royce was "Colonel Philippe Bridau." Other Balzac specialists and collectors heavily represented are Philippe Bertault, William L. Crain, Jaques (Jack) Henriquez (pseud. Ki Wist), Ethel Preston, Max M. Rottenberg, and Helen Elcessor Barnes Wodrada. Correspondence with Belle da Costa Greene and Herbert Cahoon of the Pierpont Morgan Library concerns the manuscript of Eugenie Grandet, which came to the Morgan through Royce. International concern over the imprisonment of Marcel Bouteron by the Nazis is reflected in correspondence of 1942. Occasional correspondents include Philippe Bertault, Rubin Cohen, Christian Gauss, Gordon S. Haight, William Somerset Maugham, André Maurois, Paul Métadier, Henri Peyre, Horatio Smith, Shea Tenenbaum, but also corporate bodies such as the Bibliothèque Nationale, the French Ambassy, NY, the Lenin Public Library of the U.S.S.R., Moscow, the Public Library, Museums, and National Gallery of Victoria, Syracuse University Press, the UNESCO, and University of Chicago Press. There are miscellaneous letters from various correspondents to Auguste Giraldi, Royce's printer and publisher of Le Messager de New York. Three undated nineteenth-century letters from Paul Lacroix to Armand Dutacq refer to Mme. Evelina Hanska, to her sister, Mme. Jules Lacroix, and to his quarrel with Balzac which interrupted his collaboration in La Revue de Paris. There is one folder of undated Royce correspondence.
Autograph material contains material by Champfleury, Henri Lavedan, Eduard Pailleron, Frederic Mistral, François Coppée, C.J. Paul Bourget, Honoré de Balzac, F.F. Arbuthnot, Mithell Kennerly, Walter R. Benjamin, Eveline de Balzac, Arnold Bennett, Marcel Bouteron, L. Duhamel-Surville de Balzac, Julius Chambers, André Chaucerel, Mary Hanford Ford, Hugo Muensterberg, Bliss Perry, Arthur Rau, George Saintsbury, Louis Adolphe Thiers, Benjamin W. Wells, Katherine P. Wormeley, Louise Imogen Guiney, order issued by the République Francaise to Mme de Balzac, Hector Berlioz. "Autograph" is here used as an archival term referring to handwritten documents.
Balzaciana contains mostly printed matter, which apart from a few exceptions is dating from the twentieth century. The series is subdivided into Balzac in the Theater, Book dealer catalogs / Inventories / Advertisements, Clippings, Portraits/Pictures, Transcriptions, Miscellany.
Balzac Society, 1942-1960, contains membership files, dinner invitations, announcements etc. of the Balzac Society of America
Printed material contains Balzac related essays and articles published in scholarly journals, magazines and newspapers. Whole issues have been moved to rare books for cataloging and can be found through SU library's catalog.
Writings, 1905-circa 1962, include drafts and printed matter under the headings addresses, essays, and books; translations; printed issues of the Bulletin of the Balzac Society (1942-1960), files containing material for the Bulletin issues; a chapter on Balzac in D.C. Cabeen's A Critical Bibliography of French Literature; works written by others; a sampling of Royce's Poetry; and miscellany. Monograph material includes successive drafts of A Balzac Bibliography and Indexes to a Balzac Bibliography and bibliographical notes for a projected supplement to A Balzac Bibliography.
Memorabilia, 1904-1963, is subdivided into the headings Clippings; Family; Photographs, Pictures, etc.; Royce on the Radio; and Miscellany. A group of materials relating to the Royce family includes a folder of legal and financial documents and seven folders of memorabilia (inscribed charts, drawings, and photographs; printed matter; and the transcripts of Radio interviews two of which are with Royce (on Dave Elman's Auction Gallery in 1945 and on Physionomie de la Semaine in 1949) and a third is a Balzac related edition of Invitation to Learning of the Columbia Broadcasting System. There are also several portraits of Royce and his wife, Eda Maria (Wallin) Royce as well as other pictures related to Royce's family and professional network and miscellany.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged chronologically, with undated material and a small amount to Auguste Giraldi at the end. Writings are subdivided alphabetically by type and within each type arranged alphabetically by title. Miscellany is arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- French; Balzac, Honoré de, 1799-1850.; Balzac, Honoré de, 1799-1850 -- Bibliography.; Balzac, Honoré de, 1799-1850 -- Societies, etc.; Bouteron, Marcel, 1877-1962.; Dargan, Edwin Preston, 1879-1940.; Hastings, Walter Scott, 1890-1962.; Middleton, George, 1880-1967.; Pommier, Jean, 1893-1973.; Royce, William Hobart, 1878-; Tenenbaum, Shea, 1910-1989.; Zweig, Stefan, 1881-1942.; Balzac Society of America.; Authors, American.; Authors, French.; Bibliographers -- United States.; Book collectors -- United States.; French literature -- 19th century.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Drafts (documents); Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Translations.; Authors.; Bibliographers.; Book collectors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Abbie A. Royce, M.D., and Eva A. Royce, 1973.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Professional
    - [chronological], 1901- Jun 1926; 8 folders (Box 39)
    - [chronological], Jul 1926-Mai 1928; 6 folders (Box 40)
    - [chronological], Jun 1928- Sep 1930; 8 folders (Box 41)
    - [chronological], Oct 1930- Mar 1932; 6 folders (Box 42)
    - [chronological], Apr 1932-Mar 1933; 4 folders (Box 43)
    - [chronological], Apr 1933-Jun 1934; 6 folders (Box 44)
    - [chronological], Jul 1934-Jul 1936; 9 folders (Box 45)
    - [chronological], Aug 1936-Jun 1939; 8 folders (Box 46)
    - [chronological], Jul 1939-Aug 1942; 6 folders (Box 47)
    - [chronological], Sep 1942-Dec 1946; 6 folders (Box 48)
    - [chronological], Jan 1947-Mar 1949; 8 folders (Box 49)
    - [chronological], Apr 1949-Sep 1950; 6 folders (Box 50)
    - [chronological], Oct 1950-Dec 1952; 9 folders (Box 51)
    - [chronological], 1953-1960; 9 folders (Box 52)
  - Professional/family
    - [chronological], 1961-1962
    - Correspondence donated by B. Dedinsky, 14 folders; from others to others, undated correspondence, correspondence with Syracuse University (1955-1960), correspondence of Daughter Abbie on behalf/regarding her father, correspondence with Daughter Abbie 1927-1955 (Box 53)
    - Syracuse University, 6 folders (Box 53)
    - Undated correspondence (Box 53)
    - From others to others (Box 53)
    - Daughter Abbie on behalf of / regarding her father (Box 53)
    - Daughter Abbie, 1927-1955 (Box 53)
  - Family
    - Daughter Eva, 1926-1944; 9 folders (Box 54)
    - Daughter Eva, mother in law, 1945-1960; 12 folders (Box 55)
    - Sister in law, Mr. & Ms. Vogel, wife, wife to daughter Eva, family correspondence, undated; 5 folders (Box 56)
- Autograph material
  "Autograph" is here used as an archival term referring to handwritten documents.
  - Numbers 301, 800-832, 836, 34 folders (Box 56)
    These folders contain the following: annotations by Champfleury on proof sheets of his "Balzac au College" (301), letter (28 Jun 1906) by Henri Lavedan (800), Eduard Pailleron (801), Frederic Mistral (29 Oct 1867, 802), poem by François Coppée (803), letter by C.J. Paul Bourget (804), corrected proof-sheets with instructions in the hand of Honoré de Balzac for his "Mémoires de deux jeunes mariées" (4 Sep 1841, 805), two letters (17 Jan/16 May 1901 by F.F. Arbuthnot to Smithers, one by Mithell Kennerly to Royce (2 Nov 1927), and a note (Oct 17 1927) by Walter R. Benjamin (806/807; Royce A1), letter by Eveline de Balzac to bookseller (808; Royce A3), Arnold Bennett's MS of "The most romantic figure in the history of fiction: Balzac-Genius and perfect fool" (809; Royce A4), the winged griffins of the Balzac type founder sent to Royce by Marcel Bouteron (translation of Bouteron's letter; (810, Royce A5), letters by Marcel Bouteron and L. Duhamel-Surville de Balzac to G. Wells (both from 11 Jan 1926; 811/812; Royce A6), 2 letters (14 Mar/15 Sep 1909) by Julius Chambers to T.P. Hyatt; 813/814, Royce A7), autograph on visiting card (1 Jan 1928) by André Chaucerel to Gabriel Wells (815, Royce A8), Mary Hanford Ford to T.P. Hyatt (816, Royce A9), letter (13 Nov 1909) by Hugo Muensterberg to T.P. Hyatt (816a, Royce A11), letter (5 May 1909) by Bliss Perry to T.P. Hyatt (817, Royce A12), letter (12 Jan 1926) by Arthur Rau to G. Wells accompanied by a note from Marcel Bouteron (818, Royce A13), Letters of English publishers to Roberts Bros., Boston (819), letter (1 Apr 1908 by George Saintsbury to T.P. Hyatt (820, Royce A16), letter (4 Nov 1834) by Louis Adolphe Thiers (French minister of the interior) to Balzac (821, Royce A17), letter (12 Oct 1909) by Benjamin W. Wells to T.P. Hyatt (822, Royce A18), five letters (1908) by Katherine P. Wormeley to T.P. Hyatt (823, Royce A19), letter by Katherine P. Wormeley to Mrs. Francis (824, Royce A20), 10 letters (1887-1893) by Katherine P. Wormeley to Mr. Niles (825, Royce A21), photostates of a letter by Balzac to M. Dablin (826, Royce A23), Balzac, B. de "Procès verbal d'autopsie d'un cheval" (6 Jun 1849; 827, Royce A24), Balzac's autograph corrections on a proof of a cover of "Scènes de la vie privée" (1844; 828, Royce A25), photostates of three letters: Balzac to M. Moret and to Guilbert de Pixerecourt, and Mme de Balzac to M. Moret (829, Royce A27a,b,c), note of the Prix de L'Ecole Centrale signed by Balzac, proviseur (830, Royce A2), Notes on Balzac by Louise Imogen Guiney (22 Nov 1890; 831), order (25 Jul 1850) issued by the République Francaise to Mme de Balzac (832), photostat of a letter by Hector Berlioz to Balzac (+ correspondence Jaque Barzun (Columbia) - Royce about authenticity of a Balzac note; 836, Royce P63)
  - Numbers 837, 1025, 1229, 1250, 1251, 1252, Royce A22, 8 folders (Box 57)
    These folders contain the following: photostates of Balzac's MS of "Ursule Mirouët" (837), a contract with Souverain (1225, 1251), letters by Balzac to Mme Lemoine (1229; before part of the autograph collection of Dr. Max Thorek), to Gosselin (1250), misc. unidentified autograph material, and of Balzac's correction on "Illusions perdues" and "La Bousse", letter to anonymous regarding the first performance of Quinola (1252)
  - Scrapbook Balzac, Ursule Mirouët (with photostats of original MS) (Box 93)
  - Miscellaneous
    See Balzaciana: Clippings: Scrapbook "Letters to Madame Hanska, Etc. for letters from Balzac, Honoré de (29 Jul 1832) and Wormeley, Katherine Prescott (15 Feb 1888), and a post card from the Roberts Brothers, Publishers (2 Jan 1889).
- Balzaciana
  - Balzac in the theater
    - "A Night Off: Or a Page From Balzac", 13 Mar 1885; satin playbill (Box 57)
    - Theater programs etc. (Box 57)
  - Book dealer catalogs / inventories / advertisements
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders; various Balzac related book catalogs, library inventories, promotion materials (Box 57)
    - Miscellaneous, 5 folders; various Balzac related book catalogs, library inventories, promotion materials (Box 92)
  - Clippings
    - Clippings, 6 folders; from "The Book Lover", misc. (Box 58)
    - Clippings, 10 folders; misc., Osterlind case, Sent by Santiago Gastaldi from Uruguay, from the literary review, related to "La physiologie du marriage", Balzac scrapbook (Box 59)
    - Balzac scrapbooks, 2 volumes, one of which is bound into Wilson, Woodrow, "A History of the American People" (Box 91)
    - Scrapbook "Ville de Tours - Centenaire de Balzac" (Oversize 8)
    - Scrapbook "Letters to Madame Hanska, Etc." (Box 93)
  - Portraits / pictures
    - Portraits / pictures, 2 folders; Balzac, Louise Antoinette Laure de Berny (Box 60)
    - Portraits and caricature of Balzac, one with a dedication to Royce signed by Helen Elcessor Barnes [Wodrada], Marcel Bouteron, et al. (Oversize 1)
    - Portrait of Balzac and illustrations for Balzac editions, publ. in London by Ch. Tile, Balzac portrait by Adrien Norgeot, "Philippe Bridau" by Henri Monnier Del, illustration by Adrien Moreau for George Barrie's Sons' Balzac edition (Vol. 21, p. 244) (Oversize 1)
    - Engraving of the Balzac statue by Auguste Rodin (Map-case 137)
    - Portrait of the young Balzac, copy of the painting with dedication by Marcel Bouteron (Map-case 137)
    - 2 Balzac portraits and 2 photographs with dedications to Royce by Elisabeth McCausland and Berenice Abbott, 1938 (Oversize 4)
    - Portrait of Evelina Hanska, photograph of the painting by Moritz Michael Daffinger (Map-case 137)
    - Ernest ...[?], drawing of the Maison de Balzac, Mar 1920 (Oversize 1)
    - Huard, Charles, illustrations for Oeuvres Completes of Balzac, 1912; Édition Conard, Paris (Oversize 3)
    - Peldmany [?], Max, drawing of a house [Maison de Balzac?] with dedication to Royce, 1930 (Oversize 4)
    - Portrait of Charles Henri Delacroix, black and white photograph of the painting with dedication on the back (Oversize 1)
    - Richter, Klaus, "Honoré de Balcack", portrait made in drypoint (Kaltnadelradierung) (Oversize 4)
  - Transcriptions
    - Letter by Friedrich Engels to Margaret Harkness (Box 60)
    - Four Balzac letters to the painter François Gérard (Box 60)
    - Balzac, Correspondence inédite, Lettres à madame de Brugnolle, 1845 (Box 60)
    - Russel, correspondence with W.B. Morris, John Rudd, Katherine P. Wormeley (Box 60)
  - Miscellany
    - Advertisements / announcements (Box 60)
    - "Alphabetical Index of Balzac's Correspondence" (Box 60)
    - "The Balzac Handy Book" [part I], containing e.g. a "List of Balzac's Works in the Order of Reading - arranged chronologically according to time of action" (Box 60)
    - "The Balzac Handy Book" [part II] (Box 61)
    - "Bibliographical Precisions on Some Works of Balzac" (Box 61)
    - Bookplates individual, 2 (Box 61)
    - Catalog of the exhibition "Balzac et son temps" (Box 61)
    - Chart showing autobiographical references in Balzac's works [?], with a dedication by Marcel Bouteron (Map-case 137)
    - 2 charts by Marcel Bouteron (Box 61)
    - Contents of the Balzac edition by Barrie (Box 61)
    - Dedication drafts, for the "Index to a Balzac Bibliography" (Box 61)
    - Illustrations to Balzac's works (Box 61)
    - Little notebook (Box 61)
    - List of the works of Balzac [hand written] (Box 61)
    - Massant, Raymond, misc. Balzac memorabilia (Box 62)
    - Misc. reference cards sent by Edwin Preston Dargan (Box 62)
    - Notes to Balzac, Le Père Goriot (ed. By Pierre-Georges Castex, Paris 1960) (Box 62)
    - Photographs of Balzac's printing office (Box 62)
    - Prospectuses of various editions of Balzac, 2 (Box 62)
    - Scrapbook "À notre Napoléon des lettres" (Box 62)
    - Various items (Box 62)
    - Fougères [poster], French and English version (Oversize 5)
    - Frontispiece of volume of the A.N. Macdonald Balzac edition "Extra Illustrated by Elbert Anderson Young", 1912 (Oversize 4)
    - Three-dimensional Balzacitems, "BALZAC" [wooden letters], portrait of Balzac [wood cut matrix], portrait of Balzac [stucco relief plaque] (Oversize 6)
- Balzac Society
  - Announcement of the foundation of the Groupe d'études Balzaciennes, French and English version (Box 62)
  - Balzac popularity questionnaire (Box 62)
  - Call to all Balzaciens to support the arrested Marcel Bouteron (Box 62)
  - Dinner attendance list (Box 62)
  - Invitations to the Annual Reunion of the Glorious Company of Balzacians of America (Box 62)
  - Invitation to the foundation meeting of a Canadian Balzac Society (Box 62)
  - List of members who should receive "Balzac and the Sociological Novel" and the prospectus to "A Balzac Bibliography" (Box 62)
  - Balzac related events (Box 62)
  - Membership files/applications (Box 62)
  - Membership files/applications, 3 folders (Box 63)
  - Membership files/file card index, 2 folders (Box 63)
  - Membership files/mailing lists (Box 63)
  - Replies to Balzac Dinner invitations or attendance (Box 63)
  - Schedule for the exhibition "Balzac et son temps" (Box 63)
  - Signatures of "Les Balzaciens" (Box 63)
  - Honoré de Balzac Birthday Dinner, 1941; photograph (Oversize 1)
- Printed material
  - Anonymous or unknown authors, A-Z by article title or topic
    - "About Balzac" (Royce catalog number: R1426) (Box 1)
    - "Account of the Balzac Exposition, New, Oct 1947" (Box 1)
    - "The Achievement of Balzac" (Box 1)
    - Advertisements for Balzac editions, in The Booklovers Magazine (Box 1)
    - "L'ami de Balzac" (Box 1)
    - "Les amis de Balzac forment une société" (Box 1)
    - "L'amitié en reserve de Balzac" (Box 1)
    - "An Anecdote of Balzac" (Box 1)
    - "Anecdotes on Balzac" (Box 1)
    - "An Anecdotic Study of Balzac as a Man" (Royce catalog number: R3469) (Box 1)
    - "Une année Balzac" (Box 1)
    - Announcement of the Balzac Dinner, 1 May 1943 (Box 1)
    - Announcement the New Balzac Postage Stamp (Box 1)
    - Article on Balzac's Annual Vintage, rue Raynouard (Box 1)
    - Article on Fournier's statue of Balzac at Tours (Box 1)
    - Article on Maison de Balzac (Box 1)
    - Aspects of Balzac (Royce catalog number: R1798) (Box 1)
    - "Autour du Balzac de Rodin" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac" (Royce catalog number: R 1462) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac" (Royce catalog number: R1527) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac" (Royce catalog number: R1780) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac" (Royce catalog number: R1915) (Box 1)
    - (N.Y.), "Balzac a l'atlier" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac à le flair d'un policier" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac: An Unpublished Story by the Great Frenchman" (Royce catalog number: R3470) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac, Das Mädchen mit den Goldaugen," Review in Schweizer Bücher-Zeitung) (Box 1)
    - (G.), "Balzac-Ausstellung im Palais Lobkowitz" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac - His Life and Career" (Royce catalog number: R1578) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac, Interesting Facts as to How He Worked Up His 'Peasants'" (Royce catalog number: R1797) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac a l'honneur" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac à Milan (1837)" (Royce catalog number: R1872) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac Admirers View Wells' Gift of Memorabilia to French Museum" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac and American Novelists" (Royce catalog number: R1454) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac and his 31 Waistcoats" [Advertisement] (Box 1)
    - "Balzac and His Secretary" (Royce catalog number: R1434) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac and His Writings" (Royce catalog number: R1588) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac and Maupassant" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac and Renan scripts bought by New York Publisher" (Royce catalog number: R1788) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac as a Psychological Enigma" (Royce catalog number: R1568) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac as a Politician" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac at Home" (Royce catalog number: R1901) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac aux Jardies" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac Centenary" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac chez lui" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac chez lui, et vu pas Stefan Zweig" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac Days" (Box 1)
    - "Le 'Balzac' de Rodin" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac en Savoie ou le 'Roman de Septembre'" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac et Bedouck" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac et la Touraine" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac et le tabac" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac et les itinéraires parisiens de la Comédie humaine" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac et les prix littéraires" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac et Madame Hanska" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac et M. Tardieu" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac et ses compatriotes" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac - Eugénie Grandet" (Royce catalog number: R2945) (Box 1)
    - "Balzac Forgets His Table Etiquette" (Box 1)
    - "A Balzac for the Beasts" (Box 1)
    - "Balzac Had Wise Friends" (Royce catalog number: R1784) (Box 1)